[roaring]
[narrator] Strange beasts
and monsters.
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated
by the magic in those words…
are called…
Hunters.
[Gon] Now!
I did it!
I figured it out!
I’ve just gotta go for the target
the moment it goes for its prey!
EXPLOSION x OF x DECEPTION
[birds chirping]
[narrator] Zevil Island, day two.
Gon has mastered the technique
that will be instrumental
in the capture of his target.
[winces in pain]
Ow! My hands are all bloody.
Well… I guess
I have been casting my fishing rod
for two straight days.
Still all that practice
has really paid off.
Now when a bird swoops down on a fish,
I can snag it every time.
If I use it the right way,
I’ll be able to steal Hisoka’s badge.
All that’s left now is to find him!
[grunts in pain]
But how am I supposed
to find Hisoka, anyway?
I guess I’ll just have to walk around
and trust my instincts to guide me.
What the--?
Why are they all gathering around me
like that?
Hm...
I think these butterflies
are attracted to the smell of blood.
[walkie-talkie beeping]
[Gitarrackur] Have you taken
your target’s badge, Hisoka?
[Hisoka] No, not yet.
You don’t even know
who your target is yet, do you?
[Hisoka] No.
[Gitarrackur] Want me to tell you?
[Hisoka] No. It doesn’t matter.
I’ll just hunt down three others.
[Gon] If I remember right,
Hisoka was injured back at the tower.
If this works,
these butterflies
might lead me right to him
It’s the guy who got shot with the arrow.
[birds chirping]
Oh, well. Better luck next year.
There he is!
[tense breathing]
[Gon] Calm down…
Calm down!
[tense breathing]
[exhales, relaxed]
I’ll just have to wait…
until he makes his move.
[Leorio Paradinight] Dammit.
Where the hell is everybody hiding?
It’s been two days,
and I haven’t seen anyone.
-[rustling]
-[gasps]
Who’s there?
[Tonpa] Whoa, hold on!
It’s just me, okay?
[Leorio] Tonpa!
So, I’m your target.
[Tonpa] Hey, wait a minute! Just relax!
I promise you’re not my target, all right?
Then prove it.
Right. Uh...
See?
Hmm...
[relieved sigh]
I guess it’s a good thing
I didn’t throw it away, huh?
There’s no point
in going after just anyone.
That’s a huge waste of time and energy.
Wait, wait, wait, wait…
Don’t tell me.
I’m not your target… am I?
Unfortunately, you’re not.
[Tonpa] Two-forty-six.
Ponzu, huh?
[gasps]
Wait, are you saying you know who that is?
Are you saying you didn’t?
Oh, well, see, uh…
I wouldn’t put it like that.
I just didn’t have the chance
to figure it out yet.
[smirks]
Do you want me to fill you in?
What?
[Tonpa]
What they look like, their weapons,
their special abilities,
and their weaknesses?
I will.
But I have one condition.
[rumbling]
Hm?
[Tonpa] I ate some nuts
that aren’t really agreeing with me.
Nuts, you say?
To be honest,
I can barely stand right now.
But you are pre-med, aren’t you?
Do you happen to have
any medicine on hand?
[upset tummy groan]
[Leorio] Whoa! Don’t crap your pants.
Antidiarrheals and pretty much
all the other basics.
That’s great! Thank you!
-Huh?
-But first, the info.
Fine. If you insist.
[Tonpa] For starters, Ponzu’s a woman.
Go on…
[Tonpa] As far as I know,
out of the 24 applicants who are left,
there are only five of them who use
some sort of chemical weapons.
Ponzu is one of ‘em.
That’s her…
She happens to specialize
in all sorts of toxins,
so you’ll want to be careful.
However, her strategy’s simple.
She just lies in wait.
[Leorio] She does?
She sets a trap and waits patiently
for her target to wander into it.
I see…
And you don’t have to worry
about anything else.
She’s not all that daunting herself,
so get her into an actual fight
and you’re guaranteed to win.
-[stomach rumbling]
-[Tonpa groans]
[Tonpa]
Still, if you find her, watch your step.
And remember to stay downwind.
She knows someone’s targeting her,
so it’s not like you can rely
on the element of surprise.
-[stomach rumbling]
-[grunts]
And that’s pretty much it.
Now gimme that medicine!
[Leorio] Okay.
But I need you to take a step back.
[groans] Just hurry!
I-- I can’t hold it in!
-[rustling]
-[gasps]
Dammit!
[Sommy chuckles]
Looks like I got your badge. Heh.
I knew you were keeping it
in your briefcase.
Tonpa! You’re working together?
[Tonpa] You bet.
And I didn’t need your medicine.
I’ve got my own.
As you might’ve guessed,
you really were my target this whole time.
But the card you just showed me...
Oh. That one’s my target.
And this one is Tonpa’s.
We traded for this little deception.
I just can’t believe you fell for it!
So, there you have it!
[yells] Damn you!
You're gonna pay for this!
[Tonpa] Whoops! [chuckles]
Tonpa! Let’s meet at the rendezvous point!
[Tonpa] Gotcha!
[Leorio] Stop right there!
You’re dead, ya hear me?
Why are you chasing me?
I’m not the one who’s got your badge!
Shut your trap!
You’re kidding me.
You still don’t get it, do ya, rookie?
That’s a shame.
What did you say?
It’s not our fault you got duped, buddy!
[growling]
Besides, forming alliances
is a great way to pass the Exam!
I can accept the latter
but never the former.
[groans]
[grunts]
Deception is the fault of the deceiver!
Kurapika!
Leorio. Would you like to team up?
HUNTER GLOSSARY
TARGET
[rustling]
[squeaking]
PLEASE DO NOT FEED
-[Tonpa snorts]
-[mice squeaking]
[Leorio] Hey!
Give me back my damn badge!
[laughing]
-If you want it, you gotta catch me!
-[monkey chatters]
[gasps]
[monkey chatters]
[squealing]
[Leorio] Okay!
I got my badge back safe and sound!
We have the badges
for numbers 16 and 118, as well.
So, hey. It was pretty lucky
that Tonpa was your target.
You saved me back there.
[Kurapika] Please, no thanks necessary.
I didn’t want Tonpa to realize I was there
which is why I hid
while you were ambushed from behind.
What?
[Kurapika] In my defense,
I had to be sure
you could handle an attack like that.
Otherwise, what use
would you be to me as a partner?
You qualified, though barely.
[Leorio] You are so full of it…
Either way,
I admit, it’s a lot easier
when you join forces.
The next four days, let’s stick together.
All right.
Well, you got your target’s badge,
so that’s a good start.
Add it to your own
and that’s a total of six points.
That’s assuming he doesn’t take it back.
And number 118's badge is only worth
one more point for either of us.
[Leorio] True.
But it might still come in handy.
All right. We need to find your target.
Number 246. Ponzu, right?
We need to stay alert.
[Kurapika] You’re telling me that?
[Leorio] Right, point taken.
[sighs]
You’ve been following me since we started.
It’s pretty damn obvious.
You wanna play?
Come on out.
[sighs]
Well? Show yourself.
Hm?
I know you’re there.
Did he notice me?
If you won’t come out,
I suppose I’ll have to come to you.
[Gon] This is it.
It’s all or nothing.
Huh?
When did he--
[groans quietly]
I seek a bout with you.
You’ll die.
[grunts]
Now’s my chance!
Ha!
[roars]
[Gon] It’s about to happen…
I’ve just got to wait
‘til he goes for the kill!
[roaring]
[Goz grunting]
Why?
Why isn’t Hisoka fighting back?
[loud roar]
[Goz panting]
I don’t get it…
Why... won’t you fight?
I only need to evade
and you’ll die eventually, yes?
[gasps]
I can tell by
the large swarm of Hemotropic butterflies
that your wounds are quite serious.
[groans]
[Hisoka]
Someone has already wounded you. Correct?
I understand wanting to end your life
fighting as a warrior.
[Goz] If that’s true…
and you really do understand...
then why?
Why do you refuse to fight me
and grant me the death I desire?
Because I have no interest in the dead.
[Goz] Wait, what?
But I’m-- I’m not--
[Hisoka]
Do you know how I know you’re dead?
Your eyes.
[Goz groans]
Bye-bye.
[Goz straining]
[roaring]
[groans]
[gasps]
[Gitarrackur] Sorry.
I was careless and he got away.
[Hisoka] Don’t lie to me.
He probably begged you to grant him
a last request and you relented.
Am I right?
[Gitarrackur]
Well, I may have felt sorry for the man.
He was going to die anyway.
You really need to stop pitying those
who serve no purpose.
But you’re guilty of that yourself.
You’ve walked away from opponents
before finishing them.
[Hisoka] I do have standards.
Why waste time on people
who are utterly useless?
I only spare those
whose premature deaths would be a waste.
Well? What about his badge?
Oh, I already took it.
I have six points now,
so I don’t really need this one.
Want it?
[Hisoka] Whose is this?
[Gitarrackur] It belonged to someone
who tried to snipe me.
That pissed me off, and so...
well, I killed ‘em.
Well.
Hmm... That’s always so much fun to watch.
[Gitarrackur]
It does take its toll on me, you know.
Ah. That’s much better.
Well, I’m gonna sleep until the deadline.
Best of luck.
It got dark really quick.
We shouldn’t let our guard down.
Nightfall is the best time for an ambush.
I know, I know.
[Hisoka] Only two points left to go.
I guess I’d better start hunting.
This is it!
Hmm...
Hm...
Look who it is.
[narrator]
Hisoka targets Kurapika and Leorio,
unaware that Gon is after his badge.
Four days remain
before the end of the Fourth Phase.
[Gon] Next time:
"Defeat x and x Disgrace"!
-Let’s shake hands!
-[Hisoka] With a nice, firm grip.